So with that we come upon using the cream app now and how do we use it?
Let's quickly go on and just copy paste this code because we're doing the same stuff
but this time with the cream app and what I'll say is I'll go to the
collections package, new Java class and I'll just call it working with
Shima. So let's have the main material again and this time I'll say a
cream app with key value pairs again or I'll just copy paste the code and we'll
make the necessary changes instead of a hash map we'll just use a
cream app right and then this is a cream app okay so integers are the IDs
strings are the values but you can reverse them or use something else which is
requirement driven again and we have the same data and then let's just print it
out and you will be surprised to see you will get this map this stream app
sorted in natural ordering of their IDs by default they're sorted by these
let's go on and run this let's see for ourselves you see we get first 43
although we are insert at 44 45 sorry Neha we get 43 which is map to smart 45
Neha three one two four three one step and one two three four back right this
is sorted in natural ordering right so otherwise it shears the same properties
as a map it allows you to store data in key value pairs go on and traverse that
with a 4-inch or a enhanced Java 5 for loop but that is what we've done
previously but here the point is what are the situations in which you're
going to use a map and that is when your requirement is to show data in key
value pairs the second requirement is you want them to be stored in natural
ordering you want them to be sorted in natural ordering out of the box you
never you never need to sort them yourself right if you need to then we have a
separate video for you in the custom sorting sorting video right but for now
if you want to get an element at a particular by a particular ID you can
do that as well with maps I'll say learners or get let us put there is
get it takes the key gives you the value I'll say for example one two three
go let me just go on and print it out it should print whack which is bound to the
ID one two three four so I run this and off we go right so that is how and when
you should use a clean up so by now we have covered the six important classes
there are others as well right which you should export right the requirement
driven but these are the common ones that use but you should know when to use
what and in what situation would you prefer using a collection class over all
others because that is the requirement that is what teammates and your team
leader would expect you would bring to the table that is in a particular
situation you're coding what kind of an athlete that is a collection class is
what you're going to use you should be able to decide that and I have just
demonstrated all the factors that go into your decision right think about it
and then I'll see you in the next video